#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/toan-nguyen-058506180 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Speech Signal Processing Audio Processing ASR

#### Certifications

**AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner** 

#### Honors-Awards

Gold medal of the Southern Olympiad 30/4 in Programming in 2014.

Vallet Shoolarship

Third place in VLLMs contest in VSLP 2023

#### **Publications**

Crossing Linguistic Horizons: Finetuning and Comprehensive Evaluation of Vietnamese Large Language Models

VLF-VQA: Vietnamese Lightweight Fusion architecture for Visual Question Answering

A Convex Optimization Based Method for Color Image Reconstruction

# Toan Nguyen

Sr. Al Engineer | M.S. in Computer Science Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

## Summary

I'm a senior AI engineer with nearly 5 years of experience in developing AI solutions from business and product needs, as well as delivering features through close collaboration with cross-functional teams. Additionally, I have achievements in AI foundation models in LLMs within academic domains. Currently, I'm expanding my work in Cloud Computing and Solution Architecture as I work toward becoming an AI solution engineer.

## Experience

MoMo (M\_Service)
Senior AI engineer
November 2024 - Present (5 months)

Vulcan Labs
Senior AI engineer
April 2024 - November 2024 (8 months)
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Developed AI solutions of mobile applications: ReHouseAI(Stable Diffusion), Solvie: MathGPT Solver (LLM Agents).
- Designed and implementing scalable AI systems and pipelines, and integrating them with cloud infrastructure.
- Conducted research on competitive GenAl features and presenting findings to C-level executives and the Product team to drive product enhancements.
- Reviewed code to ensure that its structure is optimized for cost-effective maintenance and scalability.

MainGames Indonesia Al Engineer May 2021 - April 2024 (3 years) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Developed Eklipse.gg
- Al services: Highlight detection (CV, Audio, LLM), Video editor (LLM, VLM, vector database)

- , Video classification
- Software engineering: Deployment (APIs, Queue Message), Databases
- Video encoding, transcoding, decoding
- Video downloading

Emage Al Pte. Ltd.

Computer Vision Engineer

July 2019 - April 2021 (1 year 10 months)

Vietnam

## Education

Ho Chi Minh University of Technology Master's degree, Computer Science · (2021 - 2024)

Ho Chi Minh University of Technology Engineer's degree, Computer Science · (2015 - 2020)